<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Newest Python PEPs</title>
    <link>https://peps.python.org/</link>
    <description>Newest Python Enhancement Proposals (PEPs): Information on new language features and some meta-information like release procedure and schedules.</description>
    <atom:link href="https://peps.python.org/peps.rss" rel="self"/>
    <docs>https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 01:05:34 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>PEP 821: Support for unpacking TypedDicts in Callable type hints</title>
      <link>https://peps.python.org/pep-0821/</link>
      <description>This PEP proposes allowing Unpack[TypedDict] in the parameter list inside Callable, enabling concise and type-safe ways to describe keyword-only callable signatures. Currently, Callable assumes positional-only parameters, and typing keyword-only functions requires verbose callback protocols. With this proposal, the keyword structure defined by a TypedDict can be reused directly in Callable.</description>
      <author>Daniel Sperber (github.blurry@9ox.net)</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://peps.python.org/pep-0821/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PEP 822: Dedented Multiline String (d-string)</title>
      <link>https://peps.python.org/pep-0822/</link>
      <description>This PEP proposes to add a feature that automatically removes indentation from multiline string literals.</description>
      <author>Inada Naoki (songofacandy@gmail.com)</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://peps.python.org/pep-0822/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PEP 820: PySlot: Unified slot system for the C API</title>
      <link>https://peps.python.org/pep-0820/</link>
      <description>Replace type and module slots with a new structure: a tagged anonymous union with flags. This improves type safety and allows adding new slots in a more forward-compatible way.</description>
      <author>Petr Viktorin (encukou@gmail.com)</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://peps.python.org/pep-0820/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PEP 819: JSON Package Metadata</title>
      <link>https://peps.python.org/pep-0819/</link>
      <description>This PEP proposes introducing JSON encoded core metadata and wheel file format metadata files in Python packages. Python package metadata (“core metadata”) was first defined in PEP 241 to use RFC 822 email headers to encode information about packages. This was reasonable in 2001; email messages were the only widely used, standardized text format that had a parser in the standard library. However, issues with handling different encodings, differing handling of line breaks, and other differences between implementations have caused numerous packaging bugs. Using the JSON format for encoding metadata files would eliminate a wide range of these potential issues.</description>
      <author>Emma Harper Smith (emma@python.org)</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://peps.python.org/pep-0819/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PEP 818: Adding the Core of the Pyodide Foreign Function Interface to Python</title>
      <link>https://peps.python.org/pep-0818/</link>
      <description>Pyodide is a distribution of Python for JavaScript runtimes, including browsers. Browsers are a universal computing platform. As with C for Unix family operating systems, in the browser platform all fundamental capabilities are exposed through the JavaScript language. For years, Pyodide has included a comprehensive JavaScript foreign function interface. This provides the equivalent of the os module for the JavaScript world.</description>
      <author>Hood Chatham (roberthoodchatham at gmail.com)</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://peps.python.org/pep-0818/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PEP 817: Wheel Variants: Beyond Platform Tags</title>
      <link>https://peps.python.org/pep-0817/</link>
      <description>Python’s existing wheel packaging format uses packaging:specifications/platform-compatibility-tags to specify a given wheel’s supported environments. These tags are unable to express modern hardware configurations and their features, such as the availability of GPU acceleration. The tags fail to provide custom package variants, such as builds against different dependency ABIs. These inabilities are particularly challenging for scientific computing, artificial intelligence (AI), machine learning (ML), and high-performance computing (HPC) communities.</description>
      <author>Jonathan Dekhtiar (jonathan@dekhtiar.com), Michał Górny (mgorny@quansight.com), Konstantin Schütze (konstin@mailbox.org), Ralf Gommers (ralf.gommers@gmail.com), Andrey Talman (atalman@meta.com), Charlie Marsh (charlie@astral.sh), Michael Sarahan (msarahan@gmail.com), Eli Uriegas (eliuriegas@meta.com), Barry Warsaw (barry@python.org), Donald Stufft (donald@stufft.io), Andy R. Terrel (andy.terrel@gmail.com)</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://peps.python.org/pep-0817/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PEP 815: Deprecate ``RECORD.jws`` and ``RECORD.p7s``</title>
      <link>https://peps.python.org/pep-0815/</link>
      <description>This PEP deprecates the RECORD.jws and RECORD.p7s wheel signature files. Lack of support in tooling means that these virtually unused files do not provide the security they purport. Users looking for wheel signing should instead refer to index hosted attestations.</description>
      <author>Konstantin Schütze (konstin@mailbox.org), William Woodruff (william@yossarian.net)</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://peps.python.org/pep-0815/</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PEP 814: Add frozendict built-in type</title>
      <link>https://peps.python.org/pep-0814/</link>
      <description>A new public immutable type frozendict is added to the builtins module.</description>
      <author>Victor Stinner (vstinner@python.org), Donghee Na (donghee.na@python.org)</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://peps.python.org/pep-0814/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PEP 813: The Pretty Print Protocol</title>
      <link>https://peps.python.org/pep-0813/</link>
      <description>This PEP describes the “pretty print protocol”, a collection of changes proposed to make pretty printing more customizable and convenient.</description>
      <author>Barry Warsaw (barry@python.org), Eric V. Smith (eric@trueblade.com)</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://peps.python.org/pep-0813/</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PEP 816: WASI Support</title>
      <link>https://peps.python.org/pep-0816/</link>
      <description>This PEP outlines the expected support for WASI by CPython. It contains enough details to know what WASI and WASI SDK version is expected to be supported for any release of CPython while official WASI support is specified in PEP 11.</description>
      <author>Brett Cannon (brett@python.org)</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://peps.python.org/pep-0816/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
